（忆往昔）
梅塔特隆偷走了我的能量
Metatron took my grace.
是天使 他们坠落了
Angels. They're falling.
想我了吗
Miss me?
梅塔特隆 现在你是凡人
Metatron, you're mortal now.
我们怎么除掉血印
How do we get rid of the mark?
- 我不知道 - 石碑呢
- I-I don't know. - What about the tablets?
石碑上没有关于血印的记载
No, there's nothing in them about the mark.
开枪打他
Shoot him.
不不 不 你的能量
No, no! No. Your grace.
我带你去找
I'll take you to it.
关于血印有什么发现吗
Anything about the mark?
也许 我找到了一本《诅咒之书》
Yeah, I found this "Book of the Damned."
我去查查
I'll go check it out.
查理 谢谢你
Charlie, thank you.
回头见 贱人们
Arrivederci, bitches.
罗威娜
Rowena?
不可能
Not possible.
血印不会让宿主轻易死去
The mark of cain never lets its host die easy.
你在这儿干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
救我儿子
Saving my son.
我妈说那个血印只不过是个诅咒
Mother says that mark is just a curse,
是可以去掉的
can be removed.
但是我挺好的 不劳你费心
I'm good, thanks.
我绝不相信血印就是绝症了
I don't buy that the mark is a terminal diagnosis.
肯定会有办法的 我们会找到办法的
There has to be a way, and we will find it.
好
Okay.
（如今）
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
你为什么要跟踪我
And why are you following me?
我不是在跟踪你
I ain't following you.
我是跟踪你包里的东西
I'm following what you got in your bag there.
那不是你的东西 小丫头
That don't belong to you, girl.
那是我家族的
Belongs to my family.
是吗 抱歉了 神偷
Yeah? Well, sorry, gambit.
谁找到归谁
Finders keepers.
这你无法理解
It's beyond your understanding.
你根本读不了
Hell, you can't even read it.
有人拿剑指着你的时候
Are you always so condescending.
你总这么拽吗
when someone's pointing a blade at you?
听我说
Now, you look here.
你可以砍死我 但我的人绝不会放弃
You can cut me down, but my people will never stop.
你可以像在俄国那样小心翼翼
And you can tiptoe through the tulips like you did in Russia,
或是像在阿拉斯加那样扒火车
or you can stow away on the back of a train like you did in Alaska,
但我们家族的人早晚会找到你
but soon enough, my kin will find you.
结果只能是你送命
This ends with you being dead.
你逃不了一辈子 小丫头
You can't run forever, little girl!
[邪恶力量 第10季第18集]
我们继续经典重放
Our flashback playback continues.
一首攀升至榜单第四的歌曲
with a song that climbed all the way to number four on the charts.
请听艾拉妮丝·莫莉塞特的《讽刺》
Here's Alanis Morissette's "Ironic."
不是吧
Really?
那首歌多经典啊
That song is a classic.
嗯 我懂你意思
Yeah, I hear you. I do.
你说得对
And you're right.
婚礼遭遇恶劣天气
Inclement weather on the day of your nuptials.
餐具用错了场合
and the wrong cutlery at inopportune times.
哪能算讽刺啊
is hardly ironic.
但很洗脑啊
But it sure is catchy.
有道理 个人品味没办法嘛
Yeah, fair point. Can't argue taste.
但自从我成了凡人
But since I became human,
感觉好奇怪
it's just so…strange.
有那么多的感触
All these feelings, you know?
我能感受到音乐
I mean, I can feel music.
比如之前那首歌《苏苏迪奥》
Like that last song, "Sussudio, "
我根本不懂 但还是好喜欢
I don't even know what it's about and I love it.
我一向喜欢歌词 文字 故事
I always enjoyed lyrics, words, stories.
让我起鸡皮疙瘩
Gives me goose bumps.
还有鸡皮疙瘩
And goose bumps…
简直了
Don't even get me started on those.
诡异
Creepy.
又撩人
And yet…arousing.
小卡
Cass.
我能这就杀了他吗
Can I just kill him now?
你知道我听得到吧
You know I can hear you, right?
不行 我们暂时需要他活着
No, we need him alive. For now.
等你拿回你的能量
Look, after he gives you your grace back,
你可以随意处置他
you can do whatever you want with him.
我想慢慢杀了他
Well, I'd like to kill him slowly.
我离你就两英尺啊
I am like two feet from you.
该隐血印查到什么了吗
Anything on the Mark of Cain?
每个字都听得清清楚楚
Every word… crystal clear.
没有
No.
我一直在找 哪怕微不足道的线索 但…
I mean, I've been digging for something, for anything, but…
这能行吗 小卡
I don't know, Cass.
肯定是有答案的
There is an answer out there.
我们会为迪恩找到解决办法的
We will find a cure for Dean.
真不知道你现在干吗要改变那个暴脾气
I don't know why you'd want to cure that little firecracker now.
他终于好玩点了…
He's finally interest-
继续查
Well, just keep digging.
嗯 这里没有你找的人 抱歉
Yeah, uh, no one here by that name. Sorry.
萨姆
Sam?
信号不好吗
Lose reception?
还是他挂你电话了
Or did he hang up on you?
他挂你电话了 是吧
He hung up on you, didn't he?
我在反复检查一切
So, I've been checking through everything again,
一遍遍地查
double-checking, and triple-checking, and…
血印是个诅咒
The mark is a curse.
可不是呢
Yeah, tell me about it.
不 萨姆
No, Sam, it's a…
它真的是个诅咒
It's an actual curse.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
克劳力告诉我的
Crowley told me.
或者该说罗威娜
Or rather Rowena told him.
杀我不成后 告诉他的
after she tried and failed to kill me.
发生了什么啊
What the hell happened?
血印保护了我
The mark protected me.
罗威娜倒不是跟我有什么梁子
Rowena doesn't really have a beef with me.
她是气克劳力
She was pissed at Crowley.
因为她觉得他变软了
because she thinks he's going soft.
- 她没说错 - 是啊
- She's not wrong. - Yeah, well,
他和老妈大吵了一架之后
After he and mommy dearest got into a fight…
老妈
Mommy dearest?
罗威娜是克劳力老妈
Rowena is Crowley's mother.
稍后详说
More about that later.
于是
So…
他就来把她的话告诉了我
Then he came and told me what she had said.
血印是个诅咒
The mark is an actual curse.
总之 抱歉
So, anyway, I'm sorry.
我或许早该告诉你的
I probably should've told you that.
嗯
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah, I know.
温彻斯特会计行 有什么能帮您的
Winchester accounting. How may I help you?
- 迪恩 - 查理
- Dean. - Charlie?
怎么回事 你在哪
What's going on? Where are you?
我好累 还在流血
Uh, uh, I'm exhausted and… and I'm bleeding.
我在一个电话亭里 电话亭啊
And I'm in a phone booth. A phone booth.
我以为这东西只存在于
I didn't know these things existed.
90年代的电视剧里
outside of "Bill and Ted's"…
听我说 深呼吸 丫头
Okay, hey, hey. Take a deep breath, kiddo.
我们都坐在这儿呢
Uh, we're both sitting here.
告诉我怎么回事 你怎么流血了
Tell me what happened. Why are you bleeding?
我中枪了
I, uh… I got shot.
你知道牙线拿来缝针很好使吗
Did you know dental floss works great on stitches?
我只昏过去两次
I only passed out twice,
而且我的伤口现在肯定散发薄荷清香了
and I'm pretty sure my wound is now minty fresh.
查理 你大概得去医院吧
Charlie, you probably need to go to a hospital.
不不 我没事的
No, no, I-I'm fine.
但我得去个安全的地方
I just got to get someplace safe.
他们还在追杀我
These guys are still after me.
什么人啊
What guys? Who?
混蛋南方佬
Some southern-fried d-bags.
自我挖出了《诅咒之书》他们就一直在追踪我
They've been after me since I-I dug up "The Book of the Damned."
你找到了 在哪
You found it? Where?
先是找错了几个地方 闯了几家博物馆
After some near misses and some broken-into museums,
我找到了些历史文件
I found historical documents.
并据此找到了西班牙一家修道院
that led to a monastery in Spain.
多年前就烧毁了 一片废墟
It burned down years ago, left for dead,
但我有种预感
but, uh, I had this hunch about it.
结果我还真对了
Turned out I was right.
好吧 查理 上面怎么说血印的
Okay, Charlie, what does it say about the mark?
我完全不知道
I have no fracking idea.
书里的用语
The language it's written in,
我前所未见
I've never seen anything like it.
我在修道院的地下室
I, uh… I found some research notes.
找到了埋书的修道士留下的研究笔记
in the monastery crypt, though, by the friar that buried it.
《诅咒之书》是一本咒语书
"The book of the damned" is a spell book.
是用来创造或解开
for creating or undoing.
所有诅咒的
any kind of damnation there is.
我们如果能翻译过来
We translate this thing,
我觉得就能把你的该隐血印去掉 迪恩
I think we can get the Mark of Cain off you, Dean.
查理 你就是个天才
Charlie, you're a genius.
逃命的天才
A genius fugitive.
这些追踪我的家伙 他们训练有素
I… these dudes following me, they are well-trained.
其中一个一直说什么他的家族
One of them keeps talking about his family.
家族 你知道名字吗
Family? Did you get a name?
不知道
No clue.
但我在一个人身上看到了一个纹身
I-I-I spotted a tattoo on one of them.
可能是家族徽章 看上去很邪乎
Might be a family crest. It seemed occulty.
我一把书挖出来
Soon as the book was out of the ground,
他们就蜂拥而至
they were all over me.
我
I, uh…
我不知道我还能逃多久了
I don't know how much more running I got left in me.
他们似乎有办法追踪这本书
T-they're tracking the book somehow.
那我们就得把你藏起来 查理
All right, then we need to get you off the grid, Charlie.
你现在在哪
Where are you right now?
得梅因南边
Uh, just south of Des Moines.
这样吧
Uh, okay, you know what?
我们的朋友鲍比在那一带
Our… our friend Bobby has a whole bunch of cabins.
有不少小木屋 供猎人暂住
scattered all around, places for hunters to crash.
虽然一般般
You know, it's not much,
但有些装备和传说书籍
but there's some gear and lore books,
可以供你打发时间 等我们过去
stuff to keep you busy till we get there.
好 带吃的
Okay, Bring Snacks.
也带上你们能找到的全部记录者解码戒
And every men of letters decoder ring there is.
这本书很古老 很可怕
This book is old and scary,
我从没见过这样的东西
and I've never seen anything like it.
看啊
Hey, check it out.
我在储藏室里找到的
I found this in the storage room.
衬铅 有咒文保护
It's lead-lined and warded.
如果那些人能追踪到书
If those guys are tracking this book,
这东西肯定能屏蔽它的信号
pretty sure this bad boy will take it off the radar.
准备好了吗
You ready?
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
没什么 我只是好一阵没见过你这样了
Nothing I just haven't seen you like this in a while, that's all.
- 这是首好歌啊 你闭嘴吧 - 嗯
- It's a good song, man. Shut up. - Yeah, it's…
听我说 这几周以来 糟心事
Look, man, it has been one crap sandwich after another.
一桩接一桩
for the past few weeks, okay?
你听到查理的话了
You heard Charlie.
我们有机会解决这事
We got a shot at fixing this thing,
如果这还不能让你振奋
so if that don't put gas in your tank, well…
你这个「机会」是一本我们读不懂的书里的咒语
If by "shot, " you mean a spell in a book that we can't read.
而且这本书目前在被人追踪
that's currently being tracked…
我们该赢一把了
We're due for a win, okay?
早该了
Overdue.
我再告诉你一件事 如果这事真成了
I'll tell you another thing, if this actually does work,
我们要休一阵
we're gonna take some time off.
度假吗
What, like a vacation?
而且不是去维加斯度个周末
And I'm not talking just like a weekend in vegas.
或是在哪个破旅馆里 看付费黄片
or sitting in some crap motel watching pay-per-porn.
不 我要去海滩
No, I'm talking about a beach.
喝鸡尾酒 去游泳
Drinking cervezas, go for a swim,
跟当地野生动物一起玩
mingle with the local wildlife.
我们上次去海滩都是什么时候了
When was the last time either one of us was on a beach?
从没去过
Never.
没错
脚踩在沙滩上 萨姆
Sand between our toes, Sammy.
脚踩在沙滩上
Sand between our toes.
我的我（上帝）啊
O…m…me.
食物
Food.
美味的食物
Glorious food.
那么多书里 有那么丰富的描绘
All the countless descriptions in so many books,
但那也只是言语
but those are just words.
这味道 真实的味道
The taste, the… the actual taste…
我根本不知道
I had no idea.
还有这个过程
And the process…
这里进
Goes in here…
这里出
Comes out here.
简直是巫术
Sorcery.
你也做过人类
I mean, you used to be human.
你不想念这一切吗
Don't you miss all this?
不 我不想念消化
No. I don't miss digestion.
也不想念消化不良
I don't miss indigestion.
不不 不是那个
No, no, no. Not that.
你不想念这一切的感觉吗
I mean, don't you miss the feeling of all of this?
比如这华夫饼的味道
Like the taste of these waffles.
孩子的笑声
The sound of a child's laughter.
看看我们啊
Look at us.
我们这两个天使
We're a couple of angels who've touched.
不仅接触过神明 也知晓人性
not only the divine, but the mundane.
我们有很多共同点
You and I have a lot in common.
少来
Don't.
怎么了
What?
我以为我们挺愉快呢
I thought we were having a moment.
我们就不能做好闺蜜吗
Can't we be besties?
休想
No.
因为你杀了我朋友
Because you killed my friend.
拜托 迪恩不是没事吗 基本没事吧
Oh, pbht. Dean is fine, mostly.
你就不能忘了那事吗
Can't you get past that?
不可能
Never.
我们已经找了你三个安全屋了
Now, we've hit three of your so-called safe houses,
却都空无一物
and all of them are empty.
所以你要么是把我的能量弄丢了
So either you've lost my grace.
要么你是在拖延
or you're stalling.
你能怪我吗
Can you blame me?
我一交出你的能量 我就死定了
The minute I hand over your grace, I'm dead.
你是自作自受 梅塔特隆
You have made your bed, Metatron,
你休想逃避你的命运了
And nothing is going to get you out of it.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
我得去下洗手间
I think I need to use the little boys' room.
帮帮忙
Little help.
快点
Quick.
查理
Charlie?
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
有人跟踪你们吗
Were you followed?
没有
No, no.
你怎么样了
How you feeling?
我刚刚可能昏过去了 但我好多了
I may have just passed out, but better.
书呢
Where's the book?
我目前查到了这些
Okay, here's what I've learned so far.
大概七百年前 一个修女看到了「黑暗幻象」
About 700 years ago, a nun locked herself away.
于是把自己关了起来
after having "visions of darkness."
独自躲了几十年后
After a few decades squirrelled away by herself,
她带着这个重新出现了
she emerged with this.
每一页都是用她自己的皮肤做的
Each page is made out of slices of her own skin.
用她的血书成
written in her blood.
我说了 很诡异
I told you, it's eekish.
据我找到的笔记说
According to the notes I found,
书一直在各种邪教 巫师团之间辗转
it's been owned and used by cults, covens,
甚至还曾落入罗马教廷之手
and the Vatican had it for a while.
里面什么样的咒语都有
There's a spell inside that thing for everything.
黑弥撒 黑魔法
Talking some black mass, dark magic,
很可怕的东西
end-of-times nastiness.
至于这是什么语言
As far as what language it's written in,
我觉得是…
I'm thinking it's some kind of, uh…
迪恩 迪恩
Dean? Dean!
怎么了
What?
我觉得我最好还是别碰这东西
I don't think it's a good idea that I touch this.
我去取我们其他的东西
I'll go get the rest of our crap.
嗯
Right.
怎么回事啊
What the hell was that?
他情况并没有好转
He's not getting better.
他想掩盖
He's trying to cover, but…
我们得找到解决办法 得尽快
We need to find that cure, fast.
抱歉搞得那么乱
Sorry about the mess.
我一定是有乳糖不耐症
I guess I'm lactose intolerant.
我们再别提那事了
Let's never speak of it again.
梅塔特隆和卡西迪奥
Metatron and Castiel.
真是我的幸运日
This really must be my lucky day.
一剑二鸟
Two birds, one blade.
你是谁
Who are you?
就是个丘比特
Oh, just a cupid.
非常生气的丘比特
Just an angry, angry cupid.
我理解你的恼怒
I understand you're upset.
你们都败坏了天堂
You both corrupted heaven.
再也不能回到过去了
It's never gonna be the same!
这是我欠你的
I owed you that one, anyway.
这并不能改变什么
This changes nothing.
不客气哦
You're welcome.
我看清了那个纹身
Okay, I got a pretty good look at his tattoo.
是这样的
It's something like this.
混蛋家族 了解
The douche clan. Got it.
这就是记录者所有的异教家族的记录了
Well, this is everything men of letters had on occult families,
这里应该能找到点什么
so there should be something in here.
萨姆 有发现吗
Sam, got anything?
或许吧
Maybe.
这是一种少见的苏美尔方言
Uh, yeah, it's all in an obscure Sumerian dialect.
我在这本书中找到了大致匹配的字符
Actually found a rough match for it in this book.
太好了
Great.
我也觉得好
I thought so, too.
但我翻译了半天
But I've been translating,
翻译出来的东西都不成话
but none of the translated words make any sense.
都是胡言乱语
It's all just gibberish.
或许是另一种方言
I mean, maybe it's in a different dialect?
不不
No, no, no.
你是对的 但我觉得
You're right, but I-I think…
我觉得这是密文
I think this is in code.
一本用读不懂的语言写的密文书
An entire book of unreadable text that's also in code.
太好了
Great.
你们还自称是死书呆子呢
And you call yourselves nerds.
拜托 你们行的
Come on. You got this.
是啊
He's right.
开启阿兰·图灵模式嘛 破解密文
Let's get our Alan Turing on, decrypt this bitch.
那个 查理
You know what, Charlie?
不如
Why, uh…
我们先用我的笔记研究吧
Um, why don't we stick with my notes for a little bit?
这书真是看得我眼睛疼
This book is literally making my eyes hurt.
怎么了
What is it?
该死
Damn it.
她找到隐藏书的办法了
She found a way to hide the book.
之前还在这里
It was here.
就在这条路上
It was on this road.
她走过这条路
She was on this road.
让他们沿路找
Send the boys up and down the way,
看有没有人见过她
see if anybody saw her.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你指望我相信你把我的能量藏在了图书馆里
You expect me to believe that you hid my grace in a library?
如今都没人去图书馆了
Nobody goes to libraries anymore.
这是世界上最安全的地方了
It's the safest place in the world.
我能感觉到我的能量
I can feel my grace.
就在这里 但被你藏起来了
It's here, but you've hidden it somehow.
在哪
Where is it?
老实说 我不知道
Honestly, I have no idea.
在哪
Where is it?
我不知道 我发誓
I don't know, I swear!
我让另一个天使藏了起来 我都不知道
I had another angel hide it, even from me!
就是为了防止
You know, in case someone.
有人想折磨我得到情报
tries to torture the information out of me!
说中了吧
Case in point!
我的能量在哪
Where is my grace?
我叫那个天使把线索藏在一些我最喜欢的书里
I told the angel to hide some clues in some of my favorite books.
妈妈 可以吗
Mother, may I?
「一个人能做的最疯狂的事是什么」
"What is the maddest thing a man can do?"
这是谜语吗 答案是什么
It's a riddle? What… what's the answer?
我怎么知道 我才做了一天的人
Beats me. I've only been a man a day.
谜语的谜底
Um, the… the answer to the riddle.
会指向另一本书
will lead to another book.
在那本书里 有你的能量
And inside that book, you'll find your grace.
我们会破解的 好吗
We're gonna work this out together, okay?
团队合作
Teamwork.
好吧 就算是布莱切利四人组也破解不出来
Okay, even the Bletchley Circle couldn't crack this thing.
我已经试遍了各种密码算法
I've tried every cryptographic algorithm there is.
毫无结果
Goose egg.
或许这也好
Well, maybe that's not such a bad thing.
那些跟踪你的人
Those people following you…
各种可怕
All kinds of wrong.
几代人 几个世纪都一直很可怕
Talking multi-generational, centuries-old wrong.
斯戴恩家族
The Styne family.
根据记录者的文件 他们能追溯到19世纪初
Men of letters' files have them dated back to the early 1800s.
他们用咒语制造疾病
They used spells to create disease,
瓦解市场
to destabilize markets.
甚至在纳粹掌权前就帮过他们
Hell, they even helped the Nazis before they came into power,
还借此从中牟利
and they profited from all of it.
那么他们就是超自然的杜邦家族吗
So, they're like the supernatural Du Ponts?
差不多吧
Basically.
他们用的咒语
All the spells they used.
都来自一本「极邪恶之书」
came from a book of "Unspeakable evil, "
他们大概一百多年前弄丢了
which they lost nearly 100 years ago.
好吧 他们很坏 怎么了
Okay, so they're bad. So what?
我们对付过更坏的
We faced worse.
萨姆 好好读资料
Sam, read the file.
书的效果就是 你用书
The way the book works is when you use it,
就会产生负面反应
there is a negative reaction.
程度很强
I'm talking biblical negative.
黑魔法总是有代价的
Dark magic always comes with a price.
这我们知道 这路我们走过
We know that. We've been down that road before.
那我们至少翻译出来 看看什么内容啊
Well, let's at least translate it, see what it says.
你们不懂
You guys don't understand.
自从我看到它
The book's been calling out to me.
这书就一直在召唤我
ever since I laid eyes on it, okay?
召唤血印 我能听到 就好像它是活物
Calling out to the mark. I can hear it like it's alive.
它想要我用它 做坏事
It wants me to use it, but not for good.
我也希望这就是解答
Look, I wanted it to be the answer, too, okay?
真的
I really did.
但我们必须把书销毁
But we have got to get rid of that.
烧掉 埋了 我不管
Burn it, bury it, I don't give a damn.
我们得另想办法解决血印
We'll just have to find another way to fix the mark.
比如呢
Like what?
我不知道
I don't know.
你要放弃了吗
So, you're giving up?
我不是要放弃
No, I'm not giving up.
查理 我又不是想死
Charlie, I don't have a death wish.
就是想 我也死不了
Okay, even if I did, I can't die,
我胳膊上这东西不让我死
not with this thing on my arm.
但我能尽可能地抵抗它 直到…
What I can do is I can fight it as long as I can until…
直到什么时候
Until what?
说啊
Tell me.
直到什么时候 迪恩
Until what, Dean?
直到我看着你再次变成恶魔吗
Until I watch you become a demon again?
直到那时吗
Until then?
我做不到
I can't do that.
也不会那么做
I won't do that.
那你只能把我关起来了
Well, then you'll just have to lock me up.
像之前那样 把我锁进地堡
Bind me to the bunker like you did last time.
这什么都解决不了
That doesn't solve anything.
让我们先把书翻译了 好吗
Look, just let us translate the book, okay?
如果有治愈办法 我们就去做
If there's a cure, we'll do it.
有什么后果之后再应付
and deal with the consequences later.
我不能失去你
I can't lose you.
是吗
Really?
是的
Yeah, really.
现在改主意了吗
You change your mind on that,
上次你可不是这么说的
'cause that's not what you said last time.
别这样 你知道我不是真心的
Oh, come on, man. You know I didn't mean that.
这是我的负担 萨姆
This is my cross to bear, Sam.
我的
Mine.
那本书里没有答案的
And that book is not the answer.
我们得赶紧处理掉它
Now, we got to destroy it.
以免它落入恶人之手
before it falls into the wrong hands,
这恶人也包括我
and that includes me.
我出去兜兜风
I'm gonna go for a drive.
查理 我们刚刚忘了给你带点吃的
Uh, Charlie, we forgot to pick up your snacks.
迪恩 听我说
Dean, look…
我们可以另想办法
We'll figure out another way.
萨姆 我有天会去度假的
And, Sam, I'll get my vacation.
但不是今天 不是这样
But not today. Not like this.
萨姆
Sam.
也许他是对的
Maybe he's right.
不 一定有办法的 一定有
No, there's a way to fix it. There has to be.
你不觉得咱俩组队还挺搭的吗
You know, we really do make a good team.
有点像双口相声 只不过没说相声
Kind of like a buddy comedy without the comedy.
也不是一对
Or the buddies.
别这样嘛
Oh, now, come on.
之前在小餐馆
Back at the diner,
不是演了一出激情四射的双人动作片嘛
that was some pretty awesome dynamic-duo action.
那是一场悲剧
What we did back there was unfortunate.
不该再有兄弟姐妹丧命了
No more of our brothers and sisters should die.
兄弟姐妹
Brothers and sisters?
听听啊
Listen to you.
还念叨着公司宗旨 好像还有人在乎似的
Still spitting out the company line like anyone cares.
好像我们真是一家人似的
Like we're actually a family?
其实我们不过是一群光
When what we really are are a bunch of glowing lights.
要么自怨自艾 要么狂妄自大
filled with self-loathing or delusions of grandeur.
- 或两者皆有 - 闭嘴
- Or both. - You shut up.
不
No!
我死也要死个明白
If I'm gonna die, I want answers.
比如 你现在究竟算什么
Like, who are you now?
你显然已经不是上帝的天使了
Like, you're obviously not an angel of the Lord.
还有你这样
And what about all of this.
像《功夫》里的凯恩似的在人间行侠仗义算什么
"walking the earth like Caine from 'Kung Fu'" crap?
忙着给天堂擦屁股
Cleaning up heaven's messes.
外面还有多少变坏的天使
How many more rogue angels are there out there?
等这一切结束 你又要怎么办
And what are you gonna do once you're done with all that?
回天堂吗 得了吧
Go back to heaven? Please.
之前那个叫汉娜的天使
The angel formerly known as Hannah.
已经恢复了天堂的秩序
has restored order up top.
自上帝给天堂之门剪彩之后
Smoothest it's run since.
这是天堂运作最平稳的时期了
God cut the ribbon on the pearly gates.
所以说句真心话 卡西迪奥
So tell me, Castiel, truly,
你现在的使命究竟是什么
what is your mission now?
闭嘴 接着找
You shut up and keep looking.
好吧
Well…
不能说
cannot say…
我没尽力
I didn't try.
小可怜卡西迪奥
Poor Castiel.
游了这么远 却淹死在了一个小池塘
Swam so far just to drown in shallow waters.
是不是很讽刺
Isn't it ironic?
你说呢
Don't ya think?
刚刚迪恩是什么意思
What did Dean mean?
他说你改了主意
When he said you changed your mind?
之前 我们曾有机会
So, a while back, we had a chance to, um…
关闭地狱之门
close the gates of hell.
想要完成这件事
And in order to do that,
我必须死
I would've had to die,
我自己并不介意 真的
And I was okay with that and I am okay with that,
但迪恩接受不了
but Dean was not.
所以…
And so he, uh…
他救了你
He saved you.
对 他救了我
Yeah, he saved me.
我猜猜
And let me guess,
为了救你 他做了一些你不希望他做的事
in doing so, he did something you didn't want.
把你惹怒了
and that pissed you off.
于是你就说了一些伤人的话
And you said something that hurt him?
嗯 差不多就是这样
Yeah, that sounds about right.
兄弟啊
Brothers.
我做猎人才没多久
You know, I haven't been a hunter for very long,
但我觉得这份生活就是如此了
but it feels like this is the life.
总要面对两难的选择 死亡 或泪水
Mostly ends in Sophie's choices, death, or tears.
通常三者兼有 对吧
Usually all of the above, huh?
我的人生怎么就成了这样呢
How did this become my life?
我本打算自己开个公司 娶个女神
I mean, I was gonna own my own start-up, marry ScarJo,
发明个酷酷的东西
invent something cool.
现在我
Now I'm just…
只庆幸自己还活着
I'm just happy to be alive.
当初迪恩来大学找我
You know, when Dean came to get me at school,
我告诉自己
I-I told myself…
这是最后一次
One last job, you know?
再做一次
One more job.
然后当我
And then when … when I, um…
当我失去杰西时
When I lost Jess,
我再一次告诉自己 这是最后一次了
I, again, told myself, one more job.
但是永远有下一次
There's always one more job, you know?
一次又一次
And one more job and one more job,
之后我就回法学院 回归正常生活
and then I was gonna go back to law and … and to my life.
你们就是猎人界的「海盗罗伯茨」
You were the Dread Pirate Roberts of hunting.
是啊
Yeah.
我想我现在明白了
I guess I really understand now that…
这就是我的人生
This is my life.
我热爱它
I love it.
但我不能没有我哥一个人承受
But I can't do it without my brother.
我也不想一个人承受
I don't want to do it without my brother.
如果他不在了 我不知道我…
And if he's gone, then I don't…
我明白
I-I got it. I do.
先干重要的
All right, first things first …
找到我此行的真正目标
Find what I really came here for.
「人生成功的两个因素」
"What two things do you need to succeed in life?"
《无知和自信》
Ignorance and confidence.
是引述
They're quotes.
那么
So, uh…
你和你的小伙伴真以为
…did you and samateur hour really think.
我会没有后备计划
I wouldn't have a backup plan?
找到你了 恶魔石碑
Hello, demon tablet.
（唐吉可德）
我要带着它 去好多地方
The places I'll go with this,
还有你的能量
and your grace.
能拿到一个也不错了
Well, one out of two ain't bad.
一个人能做的最疯狂的事是什么
What's the maddest thing a man can do?
任自己死去
Let himself die.
上帝创造的生灵总有一死 不是吗
God just don't build to last, does he?
下午好 先生
Afternoon, sir.
你好啊
Howdy.
结账
There we go.
够了吗
That'll be it for you?
嗯 就这些
Uh, yeah, that's it.
好吧 一共15.75美元
Okay, then. That'll be $15.75.
你是要回家 还是只是路过
You heading home, or you just passing through?
路过
Just passing through.
这么大地方只有你一个人很孤独吧
Must get awful lonely out here all by yourself.
还过得去
Oh, I get by.
不许动
Don't move.
手放在我能看到的地方
Hands where I can see them.
不要你的找零了吗
Don't you want your change?
好了
Now…
你是谁呢
Who might you be?
哎呦
Well, hello, there.
你这么个无名之徒
Where'd a back-road nothing like you.
怎么会弄到这样的东西
get their hands on something like that?
你管我呢 斯戴恩先生
What's it to you, Mr. Styne?
我的朋友叫我雅各布
My friends call me Jacob.
我可不是你的朋友
Well, I ain't your friend.
这不会是给一个
These wouldn't happen to be treats.
红发小妞买的食物吧
for a redheaded little gal, now, would they?
你们藏了那本书 是不是
Y'all hid the book, didn't you?
我猜 是衬铅的什么东西吧
Lead-lined little number, I'm betting.
我完全不知道你在说什么
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
你不知道
You don't?
看那个
See that?
柜子后面的死人
That man back there,
他跟这一路上的卡车休息站
well, he said the same thing as all the others.
和加油站的人说的话一样
at truck stops and gas stations up and down the way.
没人见过那个红头发的姑娘
Nobody had seen that redheaded girl.
然后一个身上有血印的男人进来了
And then a man bearing that mark comes in here,
来到我面前
to me.
有些事是巧合
Well, there's coincidence,
有些事是天意
and then there's just providence.
你瞧 《诅咒之书》它想要被找到
See, "The book of the damned, " it wants to be found.
它想要回到我手中
It wants to come home.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你想用书
You want to use it.
去掉你手臂上的恩赐 是不是
to get that gift off your arm, don't you?
力量放在弱者身上就浪费了
Power is wasted on the weak.
这本书…
Now, the book…
可以去掉血印
can remove that mark.
但假如你使用了那本书
But you mess around with that,
结果将会弊远大于利
you're gonna do far more harm than good.
所以你何不做正确的事呢 小子
So, why don't you do the right thing here, boy,
告诉我书在哪里
and tell me where that book is?
嗯 我会告诉你的
Yeah, sure, I'll tell you.
再说一次 我没听见
One more time. I didn't hear you.
我说…
I said…
发生什么事了
What's going on?
斯戴恩家族 他们找到我了
The Stynes, they found me.
那些混蛋身体强化了
Those douches are all jacked up, too.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我打空了一整个弹匣才把其中一个打死
I emptied a full clip into one of them before the son of a bitch went down.
迪恩 你要用圣油干什么
Dean, what are you doing with the holy oil?
那本书里的确有祛除血印的办法
There is a cure for the mark in the book.
但是有代价的
But it comes at a price.
我们得毁了它
We got to destroy it.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
它在召唤我 萨姆 明白吗
It's calling to me, Sam, okay?
我能听见 它在召唤血印
I can hear it. It's calling to the mark.
它希望我带着书逃跑
It wants me to take the book and run away with it.
烧了它 马上
Burn it, now.
萨姆 马上烧了它
Sam, burn it now.
你个傻小子
You silly boy.
我太傻 太自私了
I was foolish, selfish.
真该直接杀了他的
Should've just killed him.
谁知道他会拿那块石碑做什么
Who knows what he'll do with that tablet?
你知道吗 小卡
Well, you know what, Cass?
你拿回了自己的能量 你满血复活了
You got your grace back. You're back.
你做了正确的事
You did the right thing.
你也做了正确的事
那本书必须被销毁
That book needed to be destroyed.
我们会找到其他办法的 萨姆
We will find another way, Sam.
我们回来了 贱人们
We're back, bitches.
那是我想的那个人吗
Is that who I think it is?
查理 这是小卡
Charlie, Cass.
小卡 这是查理
Cass, Charlie.
我还以为你没这么高呢
I thought you'd be shorter.
我把这些放进冰箱里去
I'm gonna get these to the fridge.
听说你拿回了自己的能量
Heard you got your mojo back.
是的 我的…能量
Yes, my … my grace,
已经恢复了
it's … it's been restored.
那 你不能直接…
So, can't you just, you know…
治好迪恩吗
cure Dean?
很不幸 没那么简单
Unfortunately, it's not that simple.
从来就没简单过
Never is, is it?
你觉得你能治好我的腕管吗
Do you think you could do anything about my carpal tunnel?
就这样吗
Is that it?
你的腕管和枪伤都治好了
Your carpal tunnel and your bullet wound are now healed.
但你晚上最好还是戴着护腕睡觉
You may want to continue wearing your wrist brace at night, though.
我们是不是刚刚成为死党了
Did we just become best friends?
瞧瞧这是谁来了啊
Hey, look who decided to show.
那么 你恢复了
So? You're back?
百分百
100%?
怎么做到的
How did that happen?
是汉娜的功劳
Um, it was Hannah.
她设法从梅塔特隆口中问出了
She managed to get the location of the.
我剩余能量的位置
remainder of my grace out of Metatron.
太棒了
Awesome.
我就说我们该赢一把了
I told you we were due for a win.
你能恢复太好了 兄弟
Good to have you back, pal.
我不信任你
I don't trust you.
也永远不会信
And…I never will.
但我需要帮助
But I need help.
而这正是你擅长的
And this is right in your wheelhouse.
萨姆 马上烧了它
Sam, burn it now.
你个傻小子
You silly boy.
我的家族永远不会停止寻找那本书的
My family will never stop looking for that book.
我需要把该隐血印从我哥哥身上弄掉
I need the mark of Cain off of my brother.
而我觉得…
And something tells me…
你能破解这本书
You can crack this book.
并找到解决办法
and find that cure.
唯一的问题是…
The only question is…
你愿帮我吗
will you help me?
我们谈谈条件吧
Shall we discuss terms?